parkme.com 2016-12-02

# ParkMe - Privacy Policy

**ParkMe App –** **Privacy Policy**

Effective Date: 1-15-16

Welcome to the ParkMe App (the “ **App** ”) from ParkMe, an INRIX company, and thanks for taking the time to read our Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy sets out how we collect, use, and share Personal Information that we obtain about you through the App. 

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  * What information we collect and why we collect it.

  * How we share that information.

  * Your rights and choices with regard to that information.

  * The steps we take to protect that information.

  * Limitations with regard to third party websites and content.

  * How we transfer your information.

  * How we may make changes to our Privacy Policy.

  * How you may contact us. 

_**INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**_

We gather and use Personal Information about you through the App as described below. “Personal Information” means any information about an identified or identifiable individual. 

**1.** _ **Information you provide directly to us**_

**Account information**. You may create an account in our App by registering in “Settings” with an email address and password. 

**Reports** : You may report issues with our maps to us, so that we can improve them. We will not disclose such reports to other App users. 

**Your contact information** : We may use the contact information you provide to us to communicate with you, including through e-mail communications, mobile text messages, in-App messages, and push notifications. For example, we may use your email address, phone number, or other information that you provide to us (i) to contact you to verify your email address or phone number; (ii) to contact you for administrative purposes such as customer service, to respond to your inquiries, to manage your account, or otherwise provide user support; and (iii) to provide service-related messages such as notifications, confirmations, updates, and security alerts. Where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent to send you marketing communications by electronic means.

**Payment-related information**.  We may ask you to provide us with information we need to enable you to pay for certain services or offers using the App.  This information may include information about your payment card and billing address.  If we collect this information from you, we will use a trusted third-party payment processor to process your payments, and will allow you to review your payments in the App.

_**2\. Information we obtain from your use of our App**_

**Location**. We will only collect geo-location information with your authorization and as permitted by your device settings, and we will only use it in accordance with this Policy. You may at any time opt-out of the collection of your location information via your device settings. Turning off the collection of your location information will result in not receiving data for your specific location.

**Other usage information**. When you use our App, we may record certain information from your device and your use of the App, such as feature usage and account status. We may use that information in de-identified form for analytics purposes. 

_**HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION**_

We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to marketers or third parties. We may, however, share or disclose your Personal Information as follows:

  * **Members of our group.** We may share your Personal Information to any members of our group, which includes our affiliates, subsidiaries and branch offices, to which it is reasonably necessary or desirable for us to disclose your Personal Information in order to carry out the above-mentioned information processing purposes.

  * **Service providers**. We may share your Personal Information with service providers who perform services on our behalf. When we work with service providers, we require them by contract to only use or disclose the Personal Information they process on our behalf as necessary to perform certain services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. 

  * **Compliance with laws and law enforcement**. We will share your Personal Information if we, in our good faith judgment, believe it is necessary to: (i) investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; (ii) comply with laws and legal process (including valid subpoenas, court orders, or government requests); (iii) take precautions against liability and protect the property, rights, and safety of our company, our App users, or others as required or permitted by law; (iii) enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements; (iv) prevent or stop activity we believe to be illegal, fraudulent, abusive, unethical or legally actionable; and (v) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, the security or integrity of our App or equipment used to make the App available, or any other technical issues.

  * **Business Transfers**. If our business is involved in a merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets, or bankruptcy, your Personal Information may be disclosed and otherwise transferred to an acquirer, or successor or assignee. Should such operation occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the acquirer to use your Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. Following such operation, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your Personal Information with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

  * **Other Disclosures**. We may disclose your Personal Information in other ways when we have your consent to do so.

We may share statistical data that does not identify you with App users and third party partners for reporting purposes e.g., to derive or report on traffic flows.

_**YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES**_

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request access to and receive information about the Personal Information we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information, and have the information blocked or deleted, as appropriate. The right to access Personal Information may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements. You also have the right to withdraw your consent to the collection of your Personal Information. You may at any time stop the collection of your information via the settings of your device, or by uninstalling the App. Note however that if you exercise your right of blocking or deletion, if you decline to share certain Personal Information with us, or if you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionalities of the App. 

If you receive promotional messages from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the opt-out instructions contained within the message. Even after you opt-out of receiving promotional messages from us, you may continue to receive administrative messages from us regarding the App. You may turn off push notifications through your device settings.

To exercise your rights and choices to your Personal Information, please visit the settings section in the App or contact us by using the contact details provide below under “Our Contact Information”. 

_**INFORMATION SECURITY**_

We maintain technical and organizational measures intended to protect the Personal Information we obtain about you through the App against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage. 

_**THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND CONTENT**_

Our App may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from ParkMe. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by ParkMe, we are not responsible for the websites’ content, any use of the websites, or the privacy practices of the websites. 

_**INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS**_

If you are in the European Economic Area (EEA) or other region with laws governing data collection and use that differ from those of the United States, please note that your information, including your Personal Information, may be transferred to countries located outside the EEA, in particular to the United States, and those countries may not have the same level of protection as the country in which you initially provided that information. When we transfer your Personal Information we will protect it as described in this Policy. 

_**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**_

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post the revised policy in the App, and the revised version will be effective when it is posted. If we make any material changes to this policy, we will notify you of such changes, and we will indicate when such changes will become effective.

_**OUR CONTACT INFORMATION**_

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy and the way in which we handle your Personal Information, or to exercise your rights and choices, please contact us at:

ParkMe

An INRIX Company  
10210 NE Points Drive  
Suite 400  
Kirkland, WA, USA 98033  
support@parkme.com

* * *

**ParkMe Website –** **Privacy Policy**

Effective Date: 8-15-13

ParkMe, Inc **.** ("ParkMe") provides this notice explaining our online information practices and the way your personal information is collected and used. If you do not agree with the practices explained in this policy, do not use our Mobile Applications or Website (collectively, the “Service”), and, if you have registered an account with us, disable your account through the Service or ask that your registration be cancelled by emailing us at [info@parkme.com](mailto:info@parkme.com). This policy applies only to information ParkMe collects from you in connection with your use of the Service. By using the Service, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. Capitalized terms not defined in this policy shall have the meaning set forth in the [ParkMe EULA](http://www.parkme.com/terms-of-use).

  1. **Personally Identifiable Information**

Registration is required to access certain features of the Service. As part of the registration process you may be asked for limited personal and demographic information and may be required to choose a username and password that will give you access to the Service. While most of the information we collect is used internally for site analysis and improvement, some of the demographic information in your registration data is used in compiling reports that we may disclose to our partners as part of our business. However, except as stated in Section 2 below, ParkMe will never disclose or associate with your usage of the Service any of your personally identifiable information, which consists of the following: name, postal address, telephone number, fax number, e-mail address, username.

  2. **Use and Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information**

ParkMe does not rent or sell to advertisers personally identifiable information, such as your name or e-mail address. ParkMe may use your personally identifiable information:

  1. To deliver you the Service and send you notices related to the Service, your account and necessary updates. This includes fulfilling your requests for products and services.

  2. To e-mail you our newsletter, promotions and special offers from us and our partners. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by following the link in the e-mail that we send to you or by unsubscribing in an account management area we may make available.

  3. To manage your Account and Account access, provide you with Content, purchase confirmations, support and customer service and to keep track of support and customer service requests.

  4. To determine the technical capabilities of your device and the appropriate Content to deliver to you.

ParkMe may disclose personally identifiable information to its partners in order to provide the Service, resolve service problems and correct errors in the Service (including customer inquiries, billing and credit corrections), to communicate with you about the Service, to provide you with advertising and promotional information in connection with the Service, and to enhance your experience on the Service. However, these companies do not have an independent right to share this information. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Service, we cannot provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties. ParkMe does not store customers' credit card information, and all credit card orders and information are transmitted securely for processing.

Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if ParkMe files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of ParkMe. ParkMe may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other similar request pursuant to a lawsuit or regulatory proceeding, to establish or exercise our rights, or defend against or bring legal claims. ParkMe may also use or disclose such personally identifiable information in order to investigate, prevent and take action regarding fraud or misuse of the Service, to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our Privacy Policy, the ParkMe EULA, or any other agreement between you and ParkMe, and to protect the rights, property and safety of the Service, Users and others.

  3. **Publicly Available Information**

Any and all Content you submit or otherwise upload through the Services, including personally identifying information, may be viewed or used by other users, and ParkMe, its partners, and each of their contractors and employees may view or use that Content to provide the Service and otherwise perform the tasks set forth in this Privacy Policy. Any information, including personally identifying information, that you may reveal in public portions of the Service or in communications with other Users, in online discussions, opinion boxes, or forums, is generally open to the public and is not in any way private. 

You should think carefully before publicly disclosing any personally identifiable information, or other information that you consider sensitive or confidential. What you have written may be seen and/or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict. Further, we may be unable to remove such information from the Service or prevent others from collecting or disclosing that information elsewhere.

  4. **Non-Personally identifiable and Aggregate Information**

The non-personally identifiable information that we may gather includes your gender, age, zip code, country or territory of residence, Internet Protocol (IP) address (as discussed below), the type of browser that you use, the type and nature of the content that you upload to the Service and access from the Service, the comments and communication that you enter into the Service, the links and transactions with us and with third-parties that you enter into via the Service, and other aspects of your use of the Service. ParkMe uses this information to improve the Service, conduct research, to analyze your and other User's interest in the areas of the Service, to tailor advertising and content displayed to you and other Users, to inform our partners, suppliers, and information providers about the use of the Service, and to inform our advertisers about the number and demographic composition of Users that have viewed their advertising. To do this we may combine information that we have about you with information that we obtain from business partners or other companies. We may also release aggregate demographic information about User trends to partners and other third parties, including third-party advertisers on the Service. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Service based on zip code or age group. We also retain aggregated log files of requested Content in order to report overall product usage to content partners and to evaluate User trends.

Generally, an IP address changes each time you connect to the Internet (it is a “dynamic” address). Note, however, that if you have a broadband connection, depending on your individual circumstance, it is possible that your IP address that we collect, or even perhaps a cookie we use, may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because with some broadband connections your IP address doesn’t change (it is “static”) and could be associated with your personal computer.  We will not provide your IP address to third-party advertisers.

  5. **Data Security**

ParkMe uses reasonable precautions to keep user information secure. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. However, due to the open nature of communication through the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Service, and the Service and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Service do so at their own risk. ParkMe cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online. We recommend that you use “strong” Account passwords and your best efforts to protect the privacy and security of your Account information. ParkMe is not responsible for any unauthorized access to your Account or any information obtained through such unauthorized access.

  6. **Third Party Websites and Payment Processing**

The Service may contain links to other web sites or form part of the offering of those web sites. ParkMe is not responsible for the privacy policies of these sites. If you provide any information to such third parties different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. You should review such third party's privacy policies concerning any their use of data you provide to them.

ParkMe handles all payments through third-party payment processors. Information you submit in connection with making a payment through the Services is transmitted directly to the payment processor and will not be retained by ParkMe. You understand that any online transactions you submit through a payment processor are between you and that payment processor, and ParkMe is not responsible for the actions or omissions of the third-party payment processor. YOU AGREE THAT YOU WILL INDEMNIFY AND HOLD HARMLESS PARKME AND ANY OF ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBSIDIARIES OR PARENTS, AGAINST ANY AND ALL CLAIMS ARISING FROM THE ACTS OR OMISSIONS OF A THIRD-PARTY PAYMENT PROCESSOR.

  7. **Children**

ParkMe does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use the Service nor to submit any personal information to the Service. Because ParkMe does not collect information regarding children under the age of 13, ParkMe does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If ParkMe obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database, and any associated Accounts will be terminated.

  8. **Cookies and Other Data**

ParkMe may install cookies on your computer when you use the Service, either itself or through a third party. Cookies are small files that store and may track information about your use of the Service. ParkMe may use cookies to recognize you as a repeat user of the Service, log you into your account, provide Content you may find interesting, or otherwise improve your use of the Services. Most web browsers automatically accept incoming cookies, so by using the Service you agree to the installation of cookies from ParkMe. We feel that the use of cookies enhances the operation of our site, but they are not required. You will be able to use the core features of the Service with cookies blocked. Cookies may be deleted and/or blocked through your web browser. 

As is true of most websites and mobile applications, ParkMe gathers some information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes IP address, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.  We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and to measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. We may use this information in our marketing and advertising services. 

We may also collect information about when or whether you open our emails or promotional materials, and may use “click-through URLs,” linked to particular content on the Service. We use this information to assess customer interest in particular topics and the success of our marketing and promotional efforts. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, please do not click on any text or graphic links in our email messages.  

  9. **U.S. \- EU Safe Harbor Privacy Statement  **

For personal information of employees, consumers, healthcare professionals, medical research subjects and investigators, customers, investors, and government officials that ParkMe receives from the European Economic Area, ParkMe has committed to handling such personal information in accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles. For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Website at [http://export.gov/safeharbor/](http://export.gov/safeharbor/).  

  10. **Reasonable Efforts**

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our Privacy Policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our products and services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because these products and services are still in a test phase, we may not always discover an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome User feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of our technology and business, and the security risks associated with using the Internet or mobile applications, ParkMe does not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. TO THE EXTENT PERMISSIBLE BY LAW, ParkMe SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES RELATING TO ANY ALLEGED VIOLATION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, and ParkMe’s TOTAL LIABILITY FOR SUCH ALLEGED VIOLATION SHALL BE ANY PAYMENTS MADE BY YOU TO ParkMe FOR YOUR USE OF THE SERVICE (i.e., payments for our mobile application or subscription fees, if applicable).

  11. **Modifications of the Privacy Policy**

ParkMe reserves the rights to modify its Privacy Policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the Privacy Policy on the Service. If you have established an Account, we will attempt to inform you of any modifications to this Privacy Policy that affect your obligations to ParkMe or our obligations to you. If you do not agree with any such modifications, your sole remedy is to terminate your Account and to cease using the Service. You may request to terminate your Account by emailing a request to [info@parkme.com](mailto:info@parkme.com), and we will use our commercially reasonable best efforts to remove your Account information from our database within thirty (30) days. 

Any modifications to this Privacy Policy will be effective as to you upon ParkMe posting the new Privacy Policy and/or implementation of any changes on the Service. You agree to review this Privacy Policy periodically so that you are aware of any modifications. Your continued use of the Service after any modifications indicates your acceptance of the modified Privacy Policy.

The most recent version of this Privacy Policy will be available at [parkme.com/privacy](http://www.parkme.com/privacy).

* * * 

If you have any questions or comments about this policy or have questions about our privacy practices, or to issue a complaint, contact us:

ParkMe,   
1411 5th Street, Suite 300,   
Santa Monica, CA 90401.   
_Attention: Privacy Manager_
